Silva Chijioke Michael

Frontend Engineer

Email: michaelsylva36@gmail.com Github: https://github.com/chijiooke

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/chijiooke/

Professional Summary

A **Front-end focused software Engineer** with years of experience working with mobile first web technologies. A passionate, productive and an effective communicator/ happy collaborator, current strengths are Typescript, JavaScript (libraries/Frameworks), Node and MongoDB.

An effective problem solver with a keen eye for UI details having held lead positions as a Multidisciplinary designer.

Skills & Tools

- JavaScript
- Typescript
- React
- Redux
- Git
- Node

- Next.js
- JQuery
- CSS3 + HTML5
- User Experience Research
- Ux Design
- Wireframing + Prototyping

Experience

Frontend Developer - 04/2021 to current Multonion [multonion.com], FCT, Abuja, Nigeria

- Focused on Improving systems, refactoring and building utilities for use by self and other team members which speed up development by 2x
- Lead the design and built features for team management, bidding and document management of b2b procurement system using Docker, Material Ui, styled-components, MUI, Typescript, React, Context Api, A Custom open-api Node SDK.

Web Designer (seasonal project) - 07/2021 to Present Propslot [propslot.com], Abuja, Nigeria

 Designed and built a waitlist page with over 2000+ sign ups within the first quarter with Reactjs and Mailchimp's Api. Created the application's design system, carried out user research and designed UI for Web Application (Still in progress)

Frontend Developer - 09/2020 to 03/2021 Raaxo Synergy [raaxo.ng], Abuja, Nigeria

- Worked on a robust loan management system for <u>NCDMB</u> in a team of 4 engineers using React, Redux and Styled Components, I was responsible for building UI components.
- Worked on other E commerce Projects: a bespoke clothing store, <u>food ordering system</u> amongst others working in a SAAS organization using react, styled-components, javascript, REST Apis
- Restructured and maintained legacy code

Design Lead - 07/2019 to 09/2020 NativeEdge [nativedge.com], Abuja, Nigeria

Built web sites using CMS (wordpress), Designed Brand and UI elements for clients, Lead
 Mobile App UI Design for online store

Web Designer - 07/2018 to 04/2019 **NativeEdge** , Effurun, Delta State, Nigeria

Built and managed site using wordpress, HTML, Jquery, Php

Education

BSc Mathematics - 2013-2018

Federal University of Petroleum Resources, Effurun, Delta State, Nigeria

Latest Projects

- Multonion (Typescript, REACT & NodeJS): A procurement solution (<u>showcased at MIT's Momentum Demo Day</u>) with tools for team management, bidding, admin dashboard amongst others . https://multonion.com.
- React-creditcard-validator (Typescript) // Open Source Contribution: a strongly typed open source credit card input validator built with react and typescript, with over 300 weekly downloads from 18 -24th march 2022.
 https://codesandbox.io/s/react-creditcard-validator-2lcfz7
- Propslot (React JS) // Under Construction: A property co-ownership system for young Africans in Africa and diaspora (Currently with over 2000 sign ups). https://propslot.com/